Richard English

2840 Preciso Lane Henderson, NV 89074

702-789-8326 Krukedtoe81@yahoo.com

Summary

Solution focused candidate with 20+ years' experience in various IT support roles from wireless network design and deployment to corporate PC\Server Support Specialist. Proven ability to understand and learn new or unfamiliar systems quickly. Able to work individually or integrate with a team and work professionally with end users to vendors to CEOs and everyone in between with ease.

Experience

Von Technologies, Wireless Technician

Jan 2014-Mar 2020

- Traveled to client locations to install wired and wireless guest networks for Hilton brand hotels under contract with AT&T. Worked with GM or GC for scheduling and remote AT&T NOC to install their gateway appliance. Tested circuit IP address and speed. Check circuit subnet to ensure adequate amount of circuit static IP addresses for vendor devices.
- Upgrade IOS, configuration, and installation of Cisco and Ruckus wireless controllers, Cisco switches, and access points. Install switch stacking cables and Tripplite battery back-up. Patch, document, and cable management for all CAT6 and fiber connections.
- Team Lead on many large deployments requiring identifying problems and finding solutions on a time sensitive basis. Work with various vendors and customers to ensure correct equipment is onsite to complete network installation and assign static IP addresses for various vendor equipment.
- Conducted wireless surveys and network designs using Ekahau and Airmagnet. Worked with Fluke cable tester for testing cabling issues and toner for cabling labeling issues.

Datanamics, Wireless Installer

Nov 2007-Oct 2013

- Traveled to client locations to install wired and wireless guest networks for Hilton brand hotels under contract with AT&T. Worked with GM or GC for scheduling and remote AT&T NOC to install their gateway appliance. Tested circuit IP address and speed. Check circuit subnet to ensure adequate amount of circuit static IP for vendor devices.
- Upgrade IOS, configuration, and installation of Cisco switches and access points. Setup and install Nomadix gateway appliance. Install switch stacking cables and Tripplite battery back-up. Patch, document, and cable management for all CAT6 and fiber connections.
- Conducted wireless surveys and network designs using Airmagnet. Worked with a Fluke tester for testing cabling issues and toner for cabling labeling issues.

Schnucks Markets, PC\Server Support Specialist

Feb 2000-May 2007

- Support of network connectivity including wireless, VPN\remote access, and handheld devices. Installation and maintenance for wireless home network for top executives.
- Create, document, and maintain all user accounts in Active Directory, Exchange, and Novell for corporate office. Setup server network shares, IP printers, and preform required server maintenance.

- Worked with systems development and network teams to find solutions for program reliability. Training of employees on new equipment or after OS upgrades or program updates.
- Resolve help desk tickets for PC\Network support for approximately 500 corporate Windows clients. Setup and repair of PC's, laptops, and printers.

Annex Computers, PC Technician

May 1998-Feb 2000

- Provided on-site and in-house customer support and repair of PC's, laptops, printers, and monitors.
- Design and installation of small networks and wireless. Maintained inventory of parts and customer records.

Education

John A. Logan Community College

Computer Information Systems 1996-1998